Felipe Castillo

Phone: (580) 618-4991

Email: cast6858@gmail.com

Address: 4048 E 24th Pl Tulsa, OK 74114

EDUCATION

Master of Science

- Bellevue University Omaha, NE
- Major in Data Science
 Current GPA: 3.95. June 2023

Bachelor of Science

- Northeastern State
 University, Broken Arrow, Ok
- Major in Computer Science
 Overall GPA: 3.66. May 2019

Bachelor of Arts

- University of Oklahoma, Norman, OK
- Major in Political Science
- Overall GPA: 2.8. May 2014

UiPath Advanced Certification

Confirmation: NYLGEST2CBEEQG3V

SKILLS

- Customer Service
- Eclipse and Visual Studio
 Code
- UiPath Automation
- UiPath Studios
- UiPath Robot
- UiPath Orchestrator
- Decision Analytics
- Predictive Modeling
- Data-Driven Personalization
- KPI Dashboards and BPI Plans
- Microsoft works
- Problem-solving
- Work well under pressure
- Develop Software
- Maintain Software
- JavaScript, SQL, Birt
- Data Mining and Visualization
 Tools
- Machine Learning Algorithms
- Business Intelligence
- Agile methodology

INTERESTS

- UiPath automation
- Machine learning
- Code presentation
- Scripting

PROFILE SUMMARY

Technology Analyst in UiPath Artificial Intelligence Department, with years of broad-based experience in building data-intensive applications, overcoming complex architectural, and scalability issues in diverse industries. Experienced Software Developer in Utilized organizational skills to maintain secure access to customers' personal information. Developed intricate automation based on company requirements. Proficient in **UiPath**, data processing, and data mining algorithms, as well as scripting languages, including Python and Java. Capable of creating, developing, testing, and deploying highly adaptive diverse services to translate business and functional qualifications into substantial deliverables. Able to explain automation to non-technical business audiences. Ability to design software base of UiPath Concepts and implementation.

CORE COMPETENCIES

- Strong SQL and knowledge of data extraction and manipulation techniques including the ability to stage and import large volumes of data.
- Strong Experience in UiPath Automation
- Ability to explore different directions based on data and be able to quickly change direction based on the analysis.
- Highly analytical and able to extract key insights from data then communicate them clearly and effectively to stakeholders.
- Strong programming background in at least one Java, Python, or other object-oriented programming languages.
- Provides excellent customer service and demonstrates effective communication skills.
- Possess a passion for continuous learning, strong problem-solving skills, critical thinking, and good judgment.
- Excellent analytical, problem- solving, and decision-making skills to independently make sound judgments and creative.
- Advanced proficiency level in English, Spanish, and Sign Language.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Technology Analyst

Infosys Inc, Tulsa, OK | May 2022 - Present

- Reporting to the Artificial Intelligence Team, integrating benchmarked and led the development of UiPath Automation.
- Integrate UiPath Studio with UiPath Orchestrator.
- Design and implement client solution based on client requests.
- Report to vendor and client on software design.
- Build software design based of client's proposal.
- Contribute to product feature development by following the agile software development process.
- Work closely with business analysts to understand the exact requirements of the client and document them.
- Contribute to a small cross-functional team in daily stand-ups, sprint planning meetings, and retrospectives.
- Design and implement client solutions making appropriate use of software design patterns and best practices.

Associate Software Developer

Blue Cross Blue Shield, Tulsa, OK | 2019 – April 2022

- Reporting to the Lead Developer, benchmarked and led the development of web applications utilizing Java, SQL, and JavaScript.
- Build Automation Using UiPath
- Connecting UiPath with Orchestrator
- Integrate Object-Oriented Application development concepts to develop an application.
- Contribute to product feature development by following the agile software development process.
- Work closely with business analysts to understand the exact requirements of the client.
- Contribute to a small cross-functional team in daily stand-ups, sprint planning meetings, and retrospectives.
- Design and implement client solutions making appropriate use of software design patterns and best practices.

Sales Representative

Us Cellular | 2016 - 2019

- Negotiated prices and terms of sales and service agreements and maintain customer records, using automated systems.
- Prepared sales contracts for orders obtained and submit orders for processing.
- Maintained call center database by entering information.